A Guide to the Ellen Glasgow Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10212
Ellen Glasgow Papers [1945]
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10212
25 items
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 13 Apr 1977
Scope and Content
This collection consists of twenty-five letters written by Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston between 1934 and 1944. Many of the letters are brief social ones in which Miss Glasgow mentions visits to or from Preston and members of his family, all residents of Richmond; thanks him for bouquets of yellow roses, her favorite flower which he often sent for special occasions or an illness; discusses her health; or describes her vacations in Maine. In several letters she discusses with Preston, apparently her lawyer, such legal matters as her will, her literary estate and an [animal?] shelter she started. In 1939 she asks him to escort her to the city jail and to the Negro section of Richmond so that she might do research for a book. In another letter she discusses the city pound's practice of sending dogs out of state for vivisection rather than turning them over to the S. P. C. A. She asks Preston to discuss alternatives with "Dr. Bigger."
Container List
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1934 Nov 13; ALS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1936 May 28; ALS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1938 Nov 19; ALS, 3 p. w/ env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1938 Dec 29; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1939 Aug 17; TLS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1939 Aug 29; TLS, 2 p. w/ env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1939 Oct 1; TLS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1939 Dec 22; ALS, 3 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1940 July 8; ALS, 3 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1940 July 11; ALS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1940 Sept 14; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1940 Dec 25; ALS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1941 Apr 23; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1941 Sept 18; ALS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1941 Dec 29; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1942 Apr 11; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1942 Aug 5; TLS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1942 Oct 22; TLS, 4 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1942 Dec 29; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- E[llen] G[lasgow] to Edmund M. Preston, [1943 Apr 30]; ALS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1943 July 31; TLS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1943 Oct 12; TLS, 1 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, 1944 July 25; TLS, 2 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, Easter [n.d.]; ALS, 3 p. w/env.
- Ellen Glasgow to Edmund M. Preston, Tuesday [n.d.]; ALS, 2 p. w/env.